It's a castle.
Someone's fighting?
Strolling in through the front door would be a bad idea.
Shirou, we'll go in that way!
A Battle of Legend
So that is how it is.
Wow, that's awesome!
No way! Those were all Noble Phantasms?
What the hell, man?
You're crazy powerful!
Compared to that, this guy was all bark and no bite.
This is why I can't stand meat-heads!
If you value your life, stand back, fool.
It is far too early for laughter.
Huh?
I have long since grown jaded to the sight of heroes that do not fall when cut or burned.
But I have never seen a man truly return from the dead.
It would seem your life and legends
have taken shape as a Noble Phantasm.
That Noble Phantasm is the one asset I lack.
In that sense, I suppose even I stand at a disadvantage.
Though it vexes me, it seems only the highest class of arms will work on that man.
It is said that Heracles overcame twelve penances
and was welcomed to the ranks of the gods afterward.
He is truly indomitable—
the ultimate expression of human perseverance.
My treasury, however, is the exact opposite.
It is infinite—the ultimate expression of overwhelming force.
As you can see, it overflows with weaponry to slay heroes.
Cease playing nursemaid, Heracles.
Fight me in earnest,
or every last one of your labors will be for naught.
Berserker won't lose to anyone...
because he's the strongest in the world!
He's back!
Welcome back, Kiri—
Mother?
Your mother was destroyed—
killed at the hands of the man she loved above all others.
What are you saying?
Mother said that she would become the Holy Grail
and Kiritsugu would keep her safe.
Betrayed...
You were... We were betrayed by that man.
And cast aside like mere tools.
No!
You're lying...
You're lying!
You must be!
Everything you're saying must be a lie!
Where is Kiritsugu?
I'll be okay...
I can manage on my own.
I'll be okay by myself.
They say that he died.
They say that the traitor died.
They say he went and died, never once thinking to come back for us.
I don't care.
That has nothing to do with me.
I've decided to live my life by myself.
But it has everything to do with you.
You see, he had a child.
That man had a family.
A family other than me.
A family? My little brother?
Yes. I know you'll be able to kill each other.
You'll be able to kill each other soon.
After all, the Greater Grail's flame was not extinguished.
The battle ended without resolution, so it will soon resume.
I can't wait.
I can't wait, Illyasviel!
That gives you a reason to live, just like that human, right?
It hurts... It hurts...
I don't want to do this anymore.
Why does my body have to be opened up every day?
They should just quit that stupid Holy Grail War.
We cannot.
After all, it is our duty.
The miracle that occurred a thousand years ago...
We were created in order to replicate it.
Magic?
Humanity's salvation?
That will only bring happiness to humans.
What are we living for?
We have no concept of happiness,
for we are mere tools.
We are the used, not the users.
Even Elder Acht has probably never experienced joy.
Yes. We are all nothing but tools to activate the Holy Grail.
To that end, we have suffered for a thousand years.
And then, they finally achieved you.
Achieved me?
Yes. You are the Einzberns' crowning achievement—
the fruit of the techniques that created us.
No matter how much time passes,
they will never be able to create one that surpasses you.
So if you are defeated, they will all give up.
Elder Acht will probably turn off the power source himself.
For they will have their answer:
that we are relics of the past.
Everyone will give up?
You'll all end your own lives?
Yes, the factory known as the Einzberns
will abandon their thousand years of research.
With smiles on their faces,
they will concede that they gave it their best,
but it was all for naught.
That isn't right!
You're all alive! Why do you have to die?
I'm the one who's gonna fight!
Shouldn't I be the one to die?!
Do not mourn us, sweet child.
Even if everything was for nothing, we do not mind.
Even if we cannot be saved,
we will finally be freed of our obligations.
Duty, duty... It's always about our duty!
Who do the Einzberns think they are?
We never had identities of our own!
I am Sella, and starting today, I will be looking after you.
And this is Leysritt, who has been assigned to protect you.
I-Illya... Nice to meet you.
Please forgive her.
Leysritt is still being fine-tuned—
I don't care.
Introductions are pointless.
You're all the same, anyway.
So, is the Servant here?
Yes, the summoning has already been performed.
He is the great hero of Greek myth,
Heracles.
How awe-inspiring.
Rejoice, mistress!
With a Heroic Spirit such as this, your victory is assured!
We place our lives and our meager abilities at your—
No, thank you.
I don't need anything of the sort.
Servants are nothing more than tools.
It doesn't matter who they are.
I can manage just fine on my own.
I'll win the Holy Grail War by myself.
That is wrong.
You need Berserker.
Berserker will keep you safe.
Don't make me laugh.
Servants are just familiars that are bound by rules.
If not for my Command Spells, it would betray me in an instant.
I don't trust anyone anymore.
We will now begin linking you to Berserker.
Seventy percent of your body is composed of magic circuits,
so you will receive far more Servant feedback than an ordinary Master.
Please exercise the utmost caution.
Illya, if it hurts, stop.
That doesn't matter. Let's begin.
What's going on?
What are you doing?
Move like I said, Berserker!
Move, I said!
Why won't you move?
Come on... Move!
And you call yourself the most powerful Heroic Spirit?
Come on, move!
Mistress!
Please sever the link!
Let's perform the contract ritual another time!
This is nothing.
I'll tame him soon enough, so be quiet and watch.
I won't be beaten.
I'm the most powerful Master in the world!
Huh? How did I...
Oh, right.
I was in the middle of the final test.
If I make it back to the castle alive, I can go to Fuyuki.
But I left Berserker behind.
That's okay, though.
When I get back to the castle, I'll just summon a new Servant.
I'll summon one that won't cause me pain and isn't so scary.
Berserker?
Why are you here?
I left you behind.
Why aren't you fighting?
Because of me?
Because you don't want to make me suffer?
Because you don't want to hurt me?
Get them, Berserker!
I finally understand.
You didn't protect me because I ordered you to
or because you're a Servant.
You've been protecting me of your own free will, haven't you?
You're so strong, Berserker.
He won't lose.
Berserker won't lose to the likes of him.
Because Berserker's...
He's stronger than anyone!
What was that?
Shirou...
You understand, right?
No matter what happens, don't get involved.
We have no way to fight right now.
Got it?
If you want to save people,
save yourself first, and then think about others.
Your defeat is certain.
How about it? Since you will die anyway,
why not lay down your burden at the end?
If you fight unencumbered,
you still have a chance of slaying me.
I see.
Then die with your mistress.
Don't lose,
Berserker!
In that case, I shall impose upon you the greatest of labors!
That makes eleven!
You're on your final life, Heracles!
Had you forsaken your mistress at once, you would have stood a chance.
Ultimately, were you no more than a lowly beast?
One who lived to fight?
I had hoped for better from a fellow demigod.
I did not take you to be such a fool.
Berserker!
Return to me, Berserker!
Why? I told you to come back inside me, so why won't—
It's no use, little puppet.
Behold the Chains of Heaven!
None bound by these chains may escape, not even a god.
In fact,
those with high divinity levels such as this man
are bound all the more tightly.
Did you think I would allow you
to evacuate him via Command Spell?
No!
No, Berserker...
Berserker.
Berserker... Berserker...
Shirou, I'm begging you!
Huh? It hurts...
It really hurts.
Berserker...
Where are you? I can't see you.
It's all dark. I can't see anything.
Thank goodness.
Please stay here with me forever, Berserker.
What?
What an unbelievable man.
You surpassed your own myth to the very end.
That's enough, damn it!
Even if everything's dark, I'm not scared.
Because you're strong, Berserker.
With you next to me like this, I don't have to worry.
Because you always protected me.
You might have been scary, but actually, you were kind.
You were big, just like a father.
I really wanted you to scoop me up in your arms, just once.
Yeah.
It's kinda cold, isn't it?
Does betrayal rub you the wrong way?
Caster's head must be hurting, too.
You're already messed up.
You seem to have the will to fight, but that means nothing.
It just pisses me off that there are Servants like you!
A Winter's Day, the Form Wishes Take
Next Time